A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Overseas Office, Asia, Hanoi Field Office Files FA673
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Overseas Office, Asia, Hanoi Field Office Files
1974-2000, bulk 1990-1996
1990-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA673
5.73 Cubic Feet 4 record storage boxes and 1 legal box
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Arrangement
Arranged in 6 series:
1. General Files.
2. Organization Files.
3. Economic Files.
4. International Affairs files.
5. Reproductive Health and Population files.
6. Upland Management files.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains administrative and program records.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation's office in Hanoi, Vietnam operated from 1996 to 2009. It was responsible for overseeing grants for the countries of Vietnam and (starting in 1998) Thailand. These grants focused on such areas of work as international cooperation, poverty alleviation, sexuality and reproductive health, the social sciences, arts and culture, and education.
The Ford Foundation's programming for Vietnam was carried out through its Bangkok, Thailand office in the early 1990s until the Vietnamese Government issued the Foundation a license to set up an office in 1996. The Foundation then closed its Bangkok office in 1998 and transferred responsibility for Thailand programming to the Hanoi office. By the end of the Hanoi office's first five years in operation, the Foundation had supported 227 grants comprising $31.4 million in total for Vietnam programs (The Ford Foundation's Program in Vietnam - briefing material May 2002 Board of Trustees Meeting, Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 13949-17726 (FA739F), Report 016668).
In 2009, the Ford Foundation closed its Hanoi office as well as its office in Moscow, Russia.
- General Files, 1974-2000, bulk 1992-1996; 1992-1996; I; 2.63 Cubic Feet 2 record storage boxes
  - General -- AIDS Thailand, 1996 (Box 1)
  - General -- Beijing 1995 Conference -- Fourth World Conference on Women, 1993-1995 (Box 1)
  - General -- Culture and Media, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
  - General -- Ethnic Minority -- Project Proposals, 1996 (Box 1)
  - General -- Ford Foundation History Re: Grant Funding, 1974-1992 (Box 1)
  - General -- Hanoi Office Incl. Memo Re: History of Ford Foundation Activities and Field Office in Vietnam, Opening of Hanoi Office, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - General -- Hanoi Office Re: Opening of Office, Reorganization of Bangkok Office, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - General -- Hanoi Office Opening, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - General -- Human Rights, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
  - General -- Information Management Recommendations for the Hanoi Field Office, 2000 May (Box 1)
  - General -- Memoranda and Correspondence Re: Ford Foundation Activities in/regarding Vietnam, 1993-1996 (Box 1)
  - General -- (General) Obasanjo's Visit to Vietnam (1994), 1994-1996 (Box 2)
  - General -- Organization of Vietnam Files in Bangkok Office Memorandum, 1992 September 18 (Box 2)
  - General -- Osaka Meeting on Philanthropic Cooperation in Asia and the Pacific -- Osaka, Japan (December 11-14, 1994), 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - General -- Philanthropy/NGOs, 1993-1996 (Box 2)
  - General -- Program Review, 1993 (Box 2)
  - General -- Reconstruction Conference (May 21-22, 1992), 1992 May 21-22 (Box 2)
  - General -- Senior Staff Visits, 1992-1995 (Box 2)
  - General -- Southeast Asia Office Meeting/Program Review -- Hanoi, Vietnam (October 31-November 4, 1994), 1994 October 31-November 4 (Box 2)
  - General -- Television (VTV), 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - General -- Trustees, 1992-1995 (Box 2)
  - General -- United States-Vietnam Relations, State of, 1994 (Box 2)
- Organization Files, 1990-1996; II; 2.63 Cubic Feet 2 record storage boxes
  - Organization -- American Friends Service Committee (AFSC)/Quaker Service Vietnam, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - Organization -- Asian Institute of Management (AIM), 1993-1996 (Box 2)
  - Organization -- Australian National University (ANU) -- Re: Vietnam Related Issues -- Politics, Economics, Health, etc., 1992-1996 (Box 2)
  - Organization -- CARE, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - Organization -- Carnegie Council on Ethics and International Affairs (CCEIA) and Center for Asia Pacific Studies (CAPS), 1992-1996 (Box 2)
  - Organization -- China -- Studies, Exchanges, Relationship with Vietnam, 1993-1996 (Box 3)
  - Organization -- East West Center, 1990-1996 (Box 3)
  - Organization -- Hanoi University and Hanoi Law College, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
  - Organization -- Harvard University, 1992-1996 (Box 3)
  - Organization -- Hue/Danang -- Development Programs, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Organization -- Indiana University, 1994-1996 (Box 3)
  - Organization -- Institute of International Education (IIE), 1991-1996 (Box 3)
  - Organization -- International Center for Not-For-Profit Law (ICNL), 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Organization -- University of California, Berkeley, 1993-1996 (Box 3)
  - Organization -- University of Washington and Washington Universities -- Academic Programs, 1992-1996 (Box 3)
  - Organization -- USAID, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Organization -- Vietnam-USA Society, 1995 (Box 3)
- Economic Files, 1990-1996; III; 2.63 Cubic Feet 2 record storage boxes
  - Economic -- Central Institute for Economic Management (CIEM), 1990-1994 (Box 3)
  - Economic -- Economics Institute/NEU, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Economic -- Harvard Institute for Economic Development (HIID), 1991-1994 (Box 3)
  - Economic -- National Economics University (NEU) -- General, 1992-1996 (Box 4)
- International Affairs Files, 1991-1996; IV; 1.31 Cubic Feet 1 record storage box
  - International Affairs/Relations -- General, 1991-1996 (Box 4)
  - International Affairs/Relations -- ACLS -- IIR Course Lecture Notes, 1994 (Box 4)
  - International Affairs/Relations -- Institute of Southeast Asian Studies (ISEAS), 1992-1996 (Box 4)
- Reproductive Health and Population Files, 1992-1997; V; 1.31 Cubic Feet 1 record storage box
  - Reproductive Health and Population -- General -- Women's Health, AIDS, Population Control, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Reproductive Health and Population -- General -- Fourth World Conference on Women, Family Planning, AIDS/HIV, 1993-1995 (Box 4)
  - Reproductive Health and Population -- General, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - Reproductive Health and Population -- Roundtable Discussions (Ford Foundation Leadership in Vietnam), 1997 (Box 4)
- Upland Management Files, 1991-1996; VI; 1.79 Cubic Feet 1 record storage box and 1 legal box
  - Upland Management -- General, 1991-1996 (Box 4)
  - Upland Management -- Transborder Uplands, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
  - Upland Management -- Winrock International, 1991-1995 (Box 5)
  - Upland Management -- World Neighbors, 1992-1996 (Box 5)